{
    "title": "Psychology Quiz",
    "gradeLevel": 5,
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "What is psychology?",
        "options": [
          "The study of physical health and exercise.",
          "The analysis of weather patterns and their effects.",
          "The branch of science that studies how the brain works and how the mind influences behavior in people and animals.",
          "The study of ancient artifacts and cultures."
        ],
        "score": 1,
        "correctAnswerIndex": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "What makes us choose one choice over the other?",
    "options": [
      "Random chance",
      "Behavioral Psychology",
      "Genetic predisposition",
      "The alignment of stars"
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "How is the brain the control system of the body?",
    "options": [
      "It controls only muscle movements.",
      "It stores all nutrients and energy for the body.",
      "It processes food and nutrients for the body.",
      "The brain receives signals from the rest of the body & makes sense of them."
    ],
    "score": 3,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "What does the cerebrum do?",
    "options": [
      "Helps us interpret the world around us with memory, vision, hearing, and our senses.",
      "Controls digestion and waste elimination.",
      "Regulates heart rate and blood pressure.",
      "Manages muscle reflexes and coordination."
    ],
    "score": 3,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "What does the cerebellum do?",
    "options": [
      "Processes emotional responses.",
      "Conducts motor functions like muscle movement & balance.",
      "Controls language and communication.",
      "Manages hunger and thirst."
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "What does the brain stem do?",
    "options": [
      "Controls thoughts and decision-making.",
      "Regulates vision and hearing.",
      "Manages sensory perceptions.",
      "Conducts necessary functions like breathing, heart rate, etc."
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "What did Freudian Psychology emphasize?",
    "options": [
      "That the brain controls only physical movements.",
      "That all our actions are based on the weather.",
      "That our actions and behaviors are shaped by past experiences and unconscious thoughts.",
      "That our brain works best during sleep."
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "What makes us fall for mind tricks?",
    "options": [
      "Visual and auditory illusions.",
      "Speed of Processing and Selective Attention Theory.",
      "Influence of external stimuli.",
      "Changes in atmospheric pressure."
    ],
    "score": 3,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "How do you make a short term memory?",
    "options": [
      "Feel/See something and have it registered in your brain.",
      "Write down information repeatedly.",
      "Dream about an event.",
      "Perform a physical activity."
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "How long can memories stay in short term memory for?",
    "options": [
      "Several hours.",
      "A few days.",
      "Several weeks.",
      "20-30 seconds."
    ],
    "score": 1,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "What animal was the hippocampus named after?",
    "options": [
      "Dolphin.",
      "Whale.",
      "Seahorse.",
      "Octopus."
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "What makes a memory long term?",
    "options": [
      "Experiencing it once.",
      "Experiencing the memory more than once.",
      "Forgetting it initially.",
      "Reading about it in a book."
    ],
    "score": 1,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "What is memory fading?",
    "options": [
      "When you stop reviewing the memory, it fades from your memory and gets replaced.",
      "When memories get stronger over time.",
      "When memories become more vivid and detailed.",
      "When new memories are created quickly."
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "What is targeted forgetting?",
    "options": [
      "The inability to remember anything.",
      "Remembering only selective details.",
      "Learn new information that is different to old information and 'Delete' old information while you sleep.",
      "Forgetting all information from the past month."
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Why is the nervous system important in how we respond to the world?",
    "options": [
      "It makes you run faster",
      "It allows your body to send and receive messages to and from the brain",
      "It helps your muscles grow",
      "It stores all your memories"
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Why was the hippocampus named after a seahorse?",
    "options": [
      "Because it helps humans swim like a seahorse.",
      "Because scientists wanted to name it after a sea creature.",
      "Because the shape of the hippocampus looks like a seahorse.",
      "Because seahorses have strong memories."
    ],
    "score": 3,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "What part of the brain is responsible for memory storage?",
    "options": [
      "Brain stem",
      "Hippocampus",
      "Cerebellum",
      "Amygdala"
    ],
    "score": 3,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Why is studying psychology important?",
    "options": [
      "It helps you become a faster reader and memorize historical dates.",
      "It helps you understand yourself and others, manage emotions, and explore careers like therapy and research.",
      "It teaches you how to build machines and code computers.",
      "It focuses only on solving math equations and physical health."
    ],
    "score": 1,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "What is selective attention?",
    "options": [
      "Choosing what memories to keep",
      "Remembering everything at once",
      "Listening to only music",
      "Focusing on one thing while ignoring others"
    ],
    "score": 2,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is a strategy to help remember information better?",
    "options": [
      "Ignore connections between words.",
      "Memorize words in random order only.",
      "Convert words into pictures, create stories, or group related information together.",
      "Try to memorize only one word at a time without context."
    ],
    "score": 3,
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2
      }
    ]
  }
  